Welcome back to the the moment when we bring it all together into a beautiful user interface.
다시 오신 걸 환영합니다 모든 걸 아름다운 사용자 인터페이스로 통합할 시간이네요
But first, just a quick look one more time at the inference endpoint screen in Huggingface where you
하지만 먼저 한 번 더 살펴보죠 추론 엔드포인트 스크린에서 제 실행 중인 코드를
can see my running code.
볼 수 있어요
Quine 1.57 billion chat inference.
퀴네 1요 570억 개의 채팅 추론이죠
We can.
할 수 있어요
I just wanted to show you that you can come into this and take a look at how your inference endpoint
보여드리고 싶은 게 있는데 여기로 오셔서 여러분의 추론 엔드포인트가 어떻게 실행되고 있는지 살펴보세요
is running, and you can do things like see analytics, see what's going on, see the number of requests,
분석 보기 같은 걸 할 수 있어요 어떻게 되고 있는지, 요청 수를 볼 수 있죠 제가 만들긴 했지만
which, even though I made some, is not enough to get on the radar.
레이더에 잡히기엔 충분하지 않아요
Uh, latency, CPU usage.
대기 시간과 CPU 사용도요
Oh, there we go.
저기 있네요
A little blip in CPU usage from what we just did and GPU usage.
CPU 사용량과 GPU 사용량에 작은 변화가 있네요
Nice.
좋아요
Uh, and you can also go over to cost and see that I've spent $3.64 so far on, uh, on this particular,
원가를 보시면 3달러가 사용된 걸 알 수 있어요 이 모델은 지금까지 64,000달러예요
Um, okay.
네
Now, with that in mind, let's leave it, I think, on the analytics, let's go back to our Jupyter
그걸 염두에 두고 분석은 그만두고 주피터 연구소로 돌아가죠
Um, and let's wrap this code to call Code Kwan in a nice little stream method, just like the other
코드 콴을 호출하기 위해 이 코드를 마무리하죠 멋진 스트림 메서드로요 GPT 4와 Clude
stream methods that we've already done before for GPT four and for Claude stream Quen.
스트림 Quen에서 이미 했던 다른 스트림 메서드처럼요
Same kind of method, but of course it's the same function.
같은 종류의 메서드지만 물론 같은 함수죠
It's going to do it very differently.
아주 다르게 할 거예요
It's going to create a tokenizer.
토큰라이저를 생성할 거예요
It's going to, of course, uh, turn Python into the usual messages list.
파이썬 을 일반적인 메시지 리스트로 바꿔줄 거예요
It's going to apply the chat template.
채팅 템플릿을 적용할 거예요
So we now have this in the text that is ready for tokenization.
이제 텍스트에서 토큰화 준비가 됐어요
And then we make the magical call to inference client using the URL for our endpoint and passing in
그런 다음 수증 클라이언트를 위해 URL을 이용해 수증하는 마법을 부립니다 H깅페이스 토큰을
our Huggingface token.
넘기기 위해서요
And here we are doing client text generation.
클라이언트 텍스트 생성을 하고 있는데요
Here's our text we want to stream.
여기 우리가 스트리밍할 텍스트가 있어요
And that's our max new tokens.
최대 새 토큰이에요
And then back comes the results.
그리고 결과가 나오죠
As we stream back each token we yield the total of everything so far because hopefully you remember
지금까지 우리가 준 토큰을 스트리밍하면서 지금까지의 총액을 확인하죠 그라디오가 기대하는 게
that is what Gradio expects.
그거란 걸 기억하시길 바라요
It expects to a sort of cumulative total of everything that's been received so far in all of its chunks.
지금까지 받은 모든 정보가 누적되어야 해요 모든 덩어리가요
So that function there stream collection is a companion function to the others we wrote before for stream
저 스트림 컬렉션은 전에 만든 다른 스트림 GPT와 컴패니언 기능이에요
GPT for stream Claude.
스트림 클로드요
So now we can have an optimized method that will replace the previous optimized method for optimizing
이제 최적화된 메서드를 가질 수 있습니다 코드를 최적화하는 이전의 최적화된 메서드를 대체할 수 있죠
code, which can flip between three models GPT Claude or Code Kwan.
GPT Clude나 Code K콴 세 모델 사이에서 바꿀 수 있어요
Um.
네
And here we have the total of our user interface code for Gradio.
사용자 인터페이스 그라디오 코드의 총합이 여기 있네요
Make sure I run this.
이거 꼭 돌려야 해요
Uh, so you'll remember how simple this is.
얼마나 간단한지 기억하시라고요
It's crazy.
말도 안 돼요
Uh, we have a nice little title, and then we have a row for our Python code and C plus plus code.
작지만 멋진 타이틀이 있고요 파이썬 코드와 C++ 코드가 있는 행도 있네요
We have a row for selecting the model.
모델을 선택할 행이 있어요
And now we've added code Kwon to the three to the previously two models that you could choose between.
이제 코드 권을 3개에 추가했어요 이전 두 모델 사이에서 선택할 수 있었던 것에 대해서요
And we've got a button to convert the code, a button to run Python, a button to run C plus plus,
코드를 변환하는 버튼과 파이썬을 실행하는 버튼 C++를 실행하는 버튼이 있습니다
and then some output boxes for the Python results and the cplusplus results.
파이썬 결과와 C플러스플러스 결과의 출력 상자도 있고요
And then these are the three actions.
세 가지 액션이 있어요
The three places where if a button is clicked, we take some kind of action.
버튼을 클릭하면 어떤 행동을 취하는 세 장소요
And I love the way that it just simply reads like English.
단순히 영어처럼 읽히는 게 마음에 들어요
If someone wants to convert, if they press convert button, it calls the optimize function.
누군가 변환을 원한다면 변환 버튼을 누르면 최적화 함수를 호출해요
This is the inputs and that's the output.
이게 입력이고 이게 출력이죠
If they press the Python run button, it executes Python.
파이썬 실행 버튼을 누르면 파이썬을 실행하죠
The input is the Python code, the output is the python out, and the same for the C plus plus button
입력은 파이썬 코드이고 출력은 파이썬 아웃입니다 C++ 버튼도 마찬가지고요
It should it look super simple.
아주 간단해 보여야 해요
And that's because it is super simple.
아주 간단하기 때문이죠
And with that we're going to launch it.
이제 시작할 거예요
Fingers crossed this is going to work beautifully for us.
예쁘게 나오길 기도해 보죠
All right so here is our user interface.
자, 이게 사용자 인터페이스예요
Uh, and um, what you're seeing here of course, is the Python code for the simple, uh, pi calculation.
그리고 여기 보이는 것은 파이썬 코드입니다 간단한 파이 계산을 위한 코드죠
And why not?
왜 안 되죠?
Let's just try doing it for, uh, for GPT.
GPT를 위해 한번 해 보죠
You'll remember that's the C plus plus equivalent.
C 플러스 플러스 등가라는 걸 기억하세요
Let's run the Python variation.
파이썬 변형을 실행해보죠
If I remember right this is about eight seconds.
제 기억이 맞는다면 8초 정도 걸렸어요
So we have to wait for this to count to about eight.
8까지 셀 때까지 기다려야 해요
And we should get the Python results.
파이썬 결과가 Get in get으로 나올 거예요
There it is 8.6 seconds.
8번 나왔네요 6초요
There is good old pi at least to some number of decimal places.
원주율은 소수점 이하 자리까지 있어요
And now we'll run the C plus.
이제 C+를 실행할게요
Plus that came back from GPT four.
GPT 4에서도 연락이 왔고요
And great in 0.06 of a second a nice greater than 100 x improvement.
0년에도 잘했고요 06초면 100 엑스 이상 향상된 거죠
Now one more time for Claude.
클로드를 위해 한 번 더 불러보죠
We convert the the code courtesy of Anthropic's Claude.
클로드의 코드를 변환하는 거죠
Um, there it is.
저기 있네요
And now we will run Claude's C plus.
클로드의 C 플러스도 해 볼게요
Plus.
더 있어요
And it narrowly beats, uh, GPT four again.
GPT 4를 다시 한번 간발의 차로 이기죠
But I think it has this line in here, and maybe it has allowed it to be slightly faster.
하지만 이 선 때문에 속도가 약간 빨라진 것 같아요
Maybe Claude's code really is quicker.
클로드의 코드가 더 빠를지도 몰라요
Um, they're so similar that I am suspicious.
너무 비슷해서 의심스러워요
This is.
맞아요
This all gets optimized anyway by the compiler.
컴파일러에 의해 최적화돼요
But it's possible this is consistently slightly faster.
하지만 이게 일정하게 약간 더 빠를 수도 있어요
So you may be a C plus plus expert.
C 플러스 전문가일 수도 있겠네요
That can tell me.
그걸 보면 알 수 있죠
And you may be able to try it yourself and satisfy yourself, whether on your architecture it is faster
직접 해 보고 만족할 수도 있겠죠. 당신의 구조가 빠르든 느리든
or not.
간에요.
But anyway, that is not the point.
어쨌든 중요한 건 그게 아니에요
What we're here to see is how does code quality measure up?
코드 품질이 어떻게 측정되는지 알아보려고 해요
Can it convert?
전환이 가능한가요?
Does it make sense and is it any different?
말이 되는지, 다른 점이 있는지요
Let's press the convert code button and see what happens.
코드 변환 버튼을 눌러 어떻게 되는지 보죠
So first of all as we know it's more it's got some chattiness to it.
우선, 알다시피 수다스러운 느낌이 더 강하죠
It hasn't correctly stripped out its explanation.
설명이 정확히 나오지 않았어요
So we will need to delete that.
그러니 삭제해야 해요
But we'll let it get away with that.
하지만 그렇게 하도록 놔두죠 get it
We won't ding the code model for adding that extra.
추가적인 것을 추가하는 코드 모델을 치지 않을게요.
Remember, this is all streaming right now as as we watch it from the endpoint.
기억하세요, 이건 지금 모두 스트리밍 중입니다 엔드포인트에서부터 보고 있으니까요
If I go over to here, I may need to refresh that.
여기로 가면 새로 고침이 필요할지도 몰라요
We should be seeing that we do.
그걸 봐야 해요
We do indeed see a blip of CPU and GPU as it streams back the results, I love it.
결과를 스트리밍할 때 CPU와 GPU 현상이 보여요
Uh, and so here by now, uh, go down to the, uh, sorry to our gradient screen.
이제 여기 아래를 보시면... 죄송합니다, 그라데이션 스크린으로요
Here we go.
시작할게요
Uh, we have the, the, uh, full solution.
완벽한 해결책을 찾았어요
So what we're going to do now is we're going to remove the stuff at the top, and we're going to remove
이제 상단에 있는 걸 제거하겠습니다 끝에 있는 설명도
the explanation at the end that we don't need.
제거할게요 필요 없으니까요
And we are going to run this C plus plus code to see how code Quinn has done.
이 C++ 코드를 실행해 퀸 코드가 어떻게 됐는지 보죠
Let's give it a try.
한번 해 보죠
And it ran and it was fast.
아주 빠르게 달렸죠
It was about the same as GPT four.
GPT 4와 거의 비슷했어요
Oh, I imagine it's about the same.
아마 비슷할 거예요
Uh, and I see it doesn't have that pragma thing in there, but it seems to have done a great job.
실용적인 느낌이 나진 않지만 아주 잘 만든 것 같아요
It's got the same answer.
답은 같아요
And I think that is certainly a success for code.
그게 코드에 있어서는 확실히 성공이라고 생각해요
Quinn.
퀸이에요
Uh, and again, remember the difference in model parameters code Quinn running here with its 7 billion
코드 퀸이 실행 중인 모델 매개 변수는 70억 개로 다른
parameters and compared with the, uh, the uh, hundreds of, of of, uh, sorry, there are more than
모델과 비교하면 죄송합니다 GPT 4와 클로드에는 2조 개 이상의
2 trillion parameters that you've got in GPT four and Claude.
매개 변수가 있죠
Uh, so let's now go back here and let's, let's, uh, raise the bar.
그럼 다시 돌아가서 수준을 높여 보죠
Let's make the challenge harder.
더 어려운 과제를 내 보죠
Let's change this value to be the Python hard, the code which calculates the maximum subarray sum.
이 값을 파이썬 하드 으로 바꾸겠습니다 최대 서브-러레이 합을 계산하는 코드죠
And we will see now how our open source model can handle this complicated case.
이제 오픈 소스 모델이 이 복잡한 케이스를 어떻게 처리하는지 보죠
So what's it doing its thing.
뭘 하는 거죠?
So already there is a problem.
벌써 문제가 생겼네요
There is a problem.
문제가 있어요
And that problem is that, uh, it has decided to reimplement the approach for generating random numbers,
그 문제는 임의의 숫자를 생성하는 접근법을 보류하기로 결정했다는
changing the approach that we had set with this, uh, LCG, um, technique for generating repeatable
거예요 LCG라는 기술로 구현마다 반복적이고 일관된 임의의 숫자를
and consistent random numbers between the implementations.
생성하는 거죠
Now, that's despite the fact that I very clearly put in the system prompt that it should not change
제가 분명히 시스템 프롬프트에 난수 생성 주변의 기능성 변경을 금한다고
the functionality around random number generation.
입력했는데도 말이죠.
So again, I was not able to convince Coetquen to change that strategy.
그 전략을 바꾸라고 코텡을 설득할 수 없었어요
Uh, you should experiment with this, see if you can do better.
이걸로 실험해 보세요 더 잘할 수 있는지 보죠
But I was not able to do so myself with some experimenting.
하지만 실험만으로는 그렇게 할 수 없었어요
Uh, it's almost finished.
거의 다 됐어요
There we go.
됐어요
It's done.
다 됐어요
So we will take out what comes at the end, and we will take out what comes at the beginning.
그래서 끝에 나오는 것도 빼고 처음에 나오는 것도 뺄 거예요
And now the moment of truth.
이제 진실의 순간이에요
We will run the C plus plus code from Code Kwan and scroll down.
콴 코드부터 C 플러스 플러스 코드를 실행하고 스크롤을 내리죠
Uh, and what we find is, of course, that the number does not match.
물론 그 숫자가 일치하지 않는다는 걸 알게 됐죠
If you remember the the result from before.
예전 결과를 기억한다면요
So unfortunately, Code Kwan has not been successful in replicating the number, and that's no surprise.
그래서 안타깝게도 코드 콴이 숫자를 복제하는 데 실패했는데 놀랄 일도 아니죠
That is because of course, it has, uh, got a its own random number generator.
왜냐하면 이 차에는 무작위 번호 생성기가 있거든요
Um, it's, um, done some, uh, some interesting stuff here.
흥미로운 일이 좀 있었어요
It, uh, does appear to have potentially recognized the more efficient methodology, but since the
더 효율적인 방법론을 잠재적으로 인정한 것 같지만 숫자가 일치하지 않으니
numbers don't match, we can't validate that it has, in fact done everything correctly and got the
모든 게 제대로 작동하고 숫자가 맞는지 확인할 수 없어요
So unfortunately, unfortunately, I was so very hopeful.
그래서 정말 안타깝지만 희망을 걸었어요
Codeclan did Laudably Codeclan was able to pass the the pie test, the simple test, but Codeclan did
코드클런은 파이 테스트 즉, 간단한 테스트를 통과했지만 더
stumble with the harder test and wasn't able to reproduce the same exact answer as the Python code,
어려운 테스트에 실패하고 말았습니다 파이썬 부호와 같은 답을
which was its mission.
내지 못했죠
So from that perspective, unfortunately, the frontier models come up on top.
그런 관점에서 보면 안타깝게도 개척자 모델이 우세해요
Clawed again for the win.
다시 한 번 승리를 거머쥐었죠
Uh, and Codeclan didn't quite make it.
코드클랜은 성공하지 못했죠
I will see you next time for a wrap up.
그럼 다음 시간에 마무리하죠